<!--
  Copyright (c) 2016 OpenPOWER Foundation
  
  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
  
-->

<!-- The following entity variable is used to reflect the version of the 
     template document master used for building a document.  This value
     should be set by copy of the of template used to create a new
     document and should not be changed.  Use of this value is in
     in the Abstract section in this file. --> 

<chapter version="5.0" xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
xml:id="h.t2f0ahjqjbf7.1">
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <section xml:id="h.neyvrmz5e0u7.1">
    <title>Purpose</title>
    <para>The main purpose of this Note is to define a method and a
    template to collect Physical Science use cases from scientists and
    research engineers working on Physical Science projects in the context
    and within the scope of the OpenPOWER Foundation for Physical Science
    Workgroup.</para>
    <para>An effective method (shared between all stakeholders) could
    contribute to</para>
    <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
      <listitem>
        <para>understand the workflow, starting with user
        expectations;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>help Physical Science projects maintain costs within a chosen
        envelope;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>map the functionalities to the scientific requirements;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>remove possible misunderstanding between the scientific community and
        ICT stakeholders.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para> <xref linkend="h.fjazhaptp3e8.1" /> describes the context
    and the main OPFPS workflow. The proposed method is a template reported
    in <xref linkend="h.bj00l8vcud7l.1" />  and justified in
    <xref linkend="h.d31180cwfjew.1" /> .</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="h.ml4p7h2u5bgd.1">
    <title>Scope</title>
    <para>This OPFPS WG should contribute, with the foreseen deliverables
    (WP2, WP3, and WP4) (see [1]), in a more effective process of managing the
    increasing complexity of a Physical Science project, because this could
    help to take the ICT system under control or to find new solutions that
    are at the corner of the ICT industry.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="h.zhspm95fi9e9.1">
    <title>Stakeholders identification</title>
    <para>This section describes the intended audience of this Note and of
    the OPFPS WG.</para>
    <para>Stakeholders are individuals, groups, organizations who are part or are interested to a Physical Science project. All stakeholders could be
    OPFPS members, but the participation is open also to not-OPF members. The stakeholders are:</para>
    <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
      <listitem>
        <para>physical Science community: stakeholders that are
    actively involved in the scientific project, are affected by its
    outcome or can influence its outcome, and that should provide
        requirements:</para>
    	<itemizedlist spacing="compact">
    	  <listitem>
    	    <para>scientists;</para>
    	  </listitem>
    	  <listitem>
    	    <para>research engineers.</para>
    	  </listitem>
    	</itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>ICT community: stakeholders that could provide a
        solution;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>WG participants: members of both communities that should provide
        support for collecting, analyzing and categorizing
        requirements.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="h.64nbpuogu2cr.1">
    <title>Acronyms</title>
    <para>OPF = OpenPOWER Foundation</para>
    <para>OPFPS = OpenPOWER Foundation for Physical Science</para>
    <para>WG = Workgroup</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="h.k597y24tvijd.1">
    <title>Definitions</title>
    <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
    	<listitem>
    	<para><emphasis role='bold'>Physical Science</emphasis> is any science concerned with nonliving matter,
    energy, and the physical properties of the Universe, such as physics,
    chemistry, astronomy, and geology.</para>
    </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Problem analysis:</emphasis> Problem analysis involves identifying the
        overriding problem and establishing the causes and effects related to
        that problem.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Scientific objectives:</emphasis> The scientific objectives are the goals
        of a scientific project. The scientific requirements are needed to
        reach the scientific objectives.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Scientific requirements</emphasis> A) are high-level statements that
        are needed to reach the scientific objectives/goals of the scientific
        project (and of the scientific organisation that manages the project).
        They describe the results that the project will achieve, and the
        metrics which will be used to measure its success. Scientific
        requirements must be achieved to provide value for the scientific
        project.  B) A requirement of a physical science experiment
        described in terms of the parameters to perform science (e.g. minimum
        sensitivity of a telescope, minimum angular resolution). </para>
    	<itemizedlist spacing="compact">
    	  <listitem>
    	    <para>Example: we need to observe N celestial objects in T
    	    time.</para>
    	  </listitem>
    	  <listitem>
    	    <para>Example: we need to repoint the telescope in 30 seconds.</para>
    	  </listitem>
    	</itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">System requirements:</emphasis> requirements of the HW/SW solution, i.e.
        the functional and non-functional requirements of the proposed
        system. Functional requirements define a function or a behaviour
        of a system (a list of the major features or user capabilities unique
        to the product). Non-functional requirements impose qualities
        and constraints on the design or implementation (such as performance,
        security, or reliability).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">System:</emphasis> the solution that should be proposed/developed.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
      	<para><emphasis role="bold">Big Science Projects:</emphasis> large international experiments, generally systematically organized and managed.</para>
      </listitem>	
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="h.9w8eqfcov7xi.1">
    <title>Reference</title>
    <para>[1] OPFPS charter, 2016, https://members.openpowerfoundation.org/wg/OPFPS/document/1080</para>
    <para>[2] SEI, “A Framework for Software Product Line Practice, Version
    5.0”, 2012,
    http://www.sei.cmu.edu/productlines/frame_report/req_eng.htm</para>
    <para>[3] Alistair Cockburn, “Writing Effective Use Cases”, Addison
    Wesley, 2000</para>
    <para>[4] M. Christel, K. Chang, “Issues in Requirements Elicitation”,
    CMU/SEI-92-TR-012, 1992</para>
    <para>[5] Macaulay, Linda, Fowler, Chris, Kirby, Mark, and Hutt, Andrew.
    USTM: A New Approach to Requirements Specification. Interacting with
    Computers 2(1):92-118, April 1990.</para>
    <para>[6] Robin F. Goldsmith, JD, “Conventional Requirements Model Flaw
    Misses REAL Business Requirements”, 2007, available at 
    <link xl:href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.gopromanagement.com&amp;sa=D&amp;ust=1493996251691000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFeYz4qDqEpGVfWdbi5gyI1Xp3X-A">

      <citetitle>
      https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.gopromanagement.com&amp;sa=D&amp;ust=1493996251691000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFeYz4qDqEpGVfWdbi5gyI1Xp3X-A</citetitle>
    </link> </para>
    <para>[7] Robin F. Goldsmith, JD, “BAs Will Falter Until They Learn to
    Discover REAL, Business Requirements”, IEEE 17th Requirements Engineering
    Conference (RE’09), 2009</para>
    <para>[8] Dean Leffingwell, Don Widrig, “Managing Software Requirements:
    A Use Case Approach”, 2nd Edition, 2003</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
