<!--
  Copyright (c) 2016 OpenPOWER Foundation
  
  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
  
-->

<!-- The following entity variable is used to reflect the version of the 
     template document master used for building a document.  This value
     should be set by copy of the of template used to create a new
     document and should not be changed.  Use of this value is in
     in the Abstract section in this file. --> 

<chapter version="5.0" xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
xml:id="h.bj00l8vcud7l.1">
  <title>Requirement inception method</title>
  <section xml:id="h.uc5h5eptiqau.1">
    <title>Requirement inception</title>
    <para><emphasis role='bold'>Requirement inception</emphasis> is the collection of use cases from the scientific community. The main purpose is to identify <emphasis role='bold'>system requirements</emphasis> (the requirements of a solution) that provide real value for the
    scientific project, i.e. that fulfill <emphasis role='bold'>scientific
    requirements</emphasis>. </para>
    
    <para>Two main steps are foreseen:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role='bold'>Description of the scientific problem and related scientific
        requirements.</emphasis> In this context, the WG asks scientific stakeholders to
        provide an overview/summary of their problem (with a short
        description of the scientific objectives), and to provide scientific
        requirements that could be measurable; this helps to identify the
        scientific requirements for which a possible hardware/software solution has the
        greatest impact. In this way the users will understand the real value of the
        proposed solution;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role='bold'>Definition of use cases and identification of system
        requirements</emphasis> (functional and non-functional) that are used as input
        to define a solution.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>System requirement can be divided in <emphasis>system functional requirements</emphasis>, to define a function
    or a behaviour of a system, and <emphasis>system non-functional
    requirements</emphasis>, to impose qualities and constraints on the design or
    implementation of the system (such as performance, security, or
    reliability).</para>
    <para>In <xref linkend="h.hifw4g34594y.1" /> we report the
    template, that reflects the two steps depicted above.  
    <xref linkend="h.ivq40yd8cvjz.1" /> , 
    <xref linkend="h.z8a4r4bndbdc.1" />  and 
    <xref linkend="h.k1sz7cwj362y.1" /> report a
    detailed description of the template.  
    <xref linkend="h.okc3b56431x4.1" /> is a summary.</para>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="h.k1sz7cwj362y.1">
    <title>The system (the solution)</title>
    <para>The system, for which we collect system requirements could implement a workflow,  or a data flow  of a solution for a scientific project, a software library, or a software framework that could be used in a workflow or a data flow.</para>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="h.hifw4g34594y.1">
    <title>The template</title>
    <para>Scientists, research engineers, hardware and software developers
    and vendors do not have a common language and terms; all WG participants
    need details and guidance to organize the information uniformly.
    For the purpose of this work, the use cases must be readable by all
    interested stakeholders.</para>
    <para>In this section, we propose a <emphasis role='bold'>template to collect Physical
    Science use cases</emphasis> from <emphasis role='bold'>scientific stakeholders</emphasis>. This template could
    help to collect problem statements and solution requirements. The template could by filled by scientific stakeholders, or OPF members could help scientific stakeholders to fill the template. With
    this template we will help stakeholders to extract useful information:</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>to better understand which scientific requirement the proposed solution should
        fulfill;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>to better identify use cases/workflows/functional requirements
        and the context;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>to reduce problem of scope, understanding, and presumptions
        (check Section 
        <xref linkend="h.d31180cwfjew.1"/> );</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>to avoid to omit information that is mandatory to extract 
        workflows;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>to enable solutions with a real benefit for
        scientists.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>The template is organized in sections and where some key questions
    or suggestions are presents.</para>
    <informaltable frame="all" pgwide="1" xml:id="table_label">
        <tgroup cols="2">
          <colspec colname="c1" colwidth="20*" />
          <colspec colname="c2" colwidth="80*" />
          <tbody>
            <row>
	      <?dbhtml bgcolor="#FFEAC4" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#FFEAC4" ?>
              <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">
                <para>
                  <emphasis role="bold">Scientific problem analysis</emphasis>
                </para>
              </entry>
            </row>
	    <row>
              <entry><para>Name of the <emphasis role="bold">scientific project</emphasis>
                </para></entry>
              <entry><para>
                </para></entry>
	    </row>
	    <row>
              <entry><para>Scientific <emphasis role="bold">objectives</emphasis>
                </para></entry>
              <entry><para>Write some short statements about the  objectives of the scientific 
	      project for which the scientific stakeholders want to resolve a problem.</para>
	      <para>This section is useful to put the scientific project under analysis in the 
	      general context. Define objectives, not requirements.
                </para></entry>
	    </row>
	    <row>
              <entry><para><emphasis role="bold">Scientific requirements and problem</emphasis> definition
                </para></entry>
              <entry>
		<para>Write a <emphasis role="bold">scientific problem statement</emphasis>. 
		  The statement should include:</para>
		<itemizedlist spacing="compact">
		  <listitem><para>What is the problem for the scientific project?</para></listitem>
		  <listitem><para>Who is affected by it?</para></listitem>
		  <listitem><para>What is the impact of this problem on the scientific project?</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Identify here the <emphasis role="bold">scientific requirements</emphasis> 
		that the solution can contribute to fulfill. The scientific requirements should 
		be <emphasis role="bold">measurable.</emphasis></para>

		<para><emphasis>The problem of …</emphasis></para>
		<para><emphasis>affects …</emphasis></para>
		<para><emphasis>and results in … (list scientific requirements that are not fulfilled/ 
		that is too expensive to fulfill/ that must be fulfilled)</emphasis></para>
              </entry>
	    </row>
	    <row>
              <entry><para>Known <emphasis role="bold">challenging</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">risks</emphasis>
                </para></entry>
              <entry><para>Sometimes there are challenges and risks behind the problem. It could be important to find factors that may not be immediately apparent for an external stakeholder.
</para>
	      </entry>
	    </row>
	    <row>
	      <?dbhtml bgcolor="#FFEAC4" ?><?dbfo bgcolor="#FFEAC4" ?>
              <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">
		<para><emphasis role="bold">System requirements of the solution 
		(a product/hardware-software solution)</emphasis>
                </para></entry>
	    </row>
	    <row>
              <entry><para>Outline of the <emphasis role="bold">scope</emphasis>
                </para></entry>
              <entry>
<para>Define solution system boundaries, e.g. with a context diagram or in a textual form.</para>
<para>Details are in the following sections of the table.</para>
</entry>
	    </row>
	    <row>
              	<entry><para>Benefits of a <emphasis role="bold">solution</emphasis>
                	</para>
            	</entry>
              	<entry>
              
              	<para>The resolution of these problems is also the resolution of scientific requirements, i.e. the increasing of real value for the scientific community. This contributes to define new measurable to compare different solutions. Some questions:</para> 
		<itemizedlist spacing="compact">
			<listitem><para>Is there a proposed or a current (in-operation) solution?</para></listitem>
		  	<listitem><para>Why the current (if exists)/proposed solution is it not profitable? Poor design? Too expensive?</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>What are key benefits to find a new solution for this problem?</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<para>Example. <emphasis>The current solution is... (if present). Benefits of a solution/new solution that create a new system to address the problem include: ... The solution could have a direct impact on the following scientific requirements: ...</emphasis></para>
	
                </entry>
	    </row>
	    <row>
              <entry><para><emphasis role="bold">Available technologies of the context</emphasis>
                </para></entry>
              <entry><para>List currently available technologies used in the context of the considered scientific problem.
                </para></entry>
	    </row>
	    <row>
              <entry><para><emphasis role="bold">Assumptions</emphasis>
                </para></entry>
              <entry><para>Assumptions made
                </para></entry>
	    </row>
	    <row>
              <entry><para>Description of the <emphasis role="bold">workflow</emphasis>/main functional 
	      and non-functional <emphasis role="bold">requirements</emphasis>
                </para></entry>
              <entry><para>It is possible to describe the solution in term of a workflow, a 
	      list of functional requirement (list the major features or user capabilities 
	      unique to the product) or a use case and a list of non-functional requirements.</para>
	      <para>This Note does not specify “how to” write requirements.</para>
	      <para> <emphasis role="bold">Guidelines: </emphasis> it is important to define problems parametric as some performance targets, to help to understand how different performance requirements scale. The final solution (hardware and software) depends on storage needs, computing power, and programming techniques. Some 
	      questions are provided, but feel free to add any information that you think is important:</para>
	      <orderedlist spacing="compact">
		<listitem><para>For an experiment, the data acquisition is one of the most important aspects 
		and may require technologies capable of transmitting data between sensors and acquisition 
		equipment in very short times and with low latencies. Could you describe the main system 
		requirements of your data acquisition system? (e.g. data rate, latency, need of high precision 
		synchronization protocols (PTP)). <emphasis>Example: for a scientist who needs to acquire data at a rate of 3 GB/s from a distributed network of sensors the solution is a system able to receive and store data at the same rate but with a scalability of ...</emphasis></para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>In some cases, the data must be transferred from the acquisition site to another 
		place for storage and data analysis. Could you describe the workflow? Do you need appropriate 
		protocols to ensure the integrity of the data during the transfer? Do you need compression techniques? 
		Do you need public/private interfaces to access the data? Could you provide the main system 
		requirements of your data transfer system?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>If you perform simulations, could you describe the workflow? Could you provide 
		the data rate and the storage size that your simulation generates?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Must the storage be accessible by more computing nodes simultaneously without
		any special requirements regarding performance? Must the storage be accessible by more computing
		nodes simultaneously, allowing high throughput values and the possibility of the available
		space to growth? Could you provide the main system requirements of your storage system
		(size, latency, rate, the number of read/write accesses, and so on)?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Does the storage require separate areas for data and metadata
		(e.g. to improve performance and security)?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Do you need an archive system? Could you provide the main system requirements of 
		your archive system? Do you need in-memory databases? Do you need No-SQL databases?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Do you need a data preservation system? Could you provide the size and the 
		number of years that the archive should last?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>The code used for the analysis or simulation is implemented with a distributed
		memory programming paradigm (e.g. MPI)? Or the code make use of shared memory (e.g. OpenMP)?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Do you need distributed computing frameworks (e.g. Hadoop)?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Do you need stream computing frameworks (e.g. Spark)?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Is your code single thread/multithread/multiprocessing/vectorizable?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>The code links numerical libraries? Which libraries?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>The code performs the same operation on a large amount of data (SIMD programming paradigm)?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Do you require machine learning techniques for data mining?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Do you have specific software libraries (that maybe could require porting to 
		the OpenPOWER architecture)?</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Do you need some special equipment that should be connected to the data
		acquisition or data analysis system (e.g. FPGAs)</para></listitem>
              </orderedlist></entry>
	    </row>
	    <row>
              <entry><para>Constraints
                </para></entry>
              <entry><para>Restrictions on the solution space and major dependencies to external 
	      factors outside of the project’s control:</para>
	      <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
		<listitem><para>Economics (e.g. costs, licensing issues)</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Politics (e.g. internal or external, interdepartmental issues)</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Technology (e.g. choice of technology, interface with existing technologies/platforms)</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Systems (e.g. existing system, compatibility issues)</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Environment (e.g. legal/environmental/security/standards)</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>Schedule and resources (e.g. fixed schedule, team)</para></listitem>
                </itemizedlist></entry>
	    </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </informaltable>

  </section>
  <section xml:id="h.ivq40yd8cvjz.1">
    <title>Problem analysis and scientific requirements</title>
    
    <para>This section reports a justification of the template.</para>
    
    <para>The section <emphasis role='bold'>“Scientific problem analysis”</emphasis> is a summary of the problem that the scientific project covers/want to resolve, and helps OPFPS members and
    ICT stakeholders to focus on useful information from the problem domain
    of the scientific project. This section is a summary of  the problem
    analysis performed by scientific stakeholders that help OPF members and ICT stakeholders to
    identify the real value for scientists in the resolution of their
    problems.</para>
    
    <para>The first sub-section <emphasis>“Scientific
    objectives”</emphasis> contains the identification of scientific objectives,
    i.e. the goals of the scientific project.</para>
    
    <para>The scientific requirements are needed to reach the scientific
    objectives. The sub-section <emphasis>“Scientific
    requirements and problem definition”</emphasis> helps scientific stakeholders to identify the <emphasis role='bold'>scientific
    requirements</emphasis> of the project (in analogy with the “business
    requirements” for an enterprise), and to provide a <emphasis role='bold'>metric</emphasis> that will be used to estimate
    the effectiveness of the proposed solution.</para>
    
    <para>The primary reason products/systems don’t help to improve/satisfy the right scientific requirements is because the challenging and risks of the scientific requirements have not been identified adequately or they have not been properly understood by the ICT stakeholders. The sub-section <emphasis>“Known challenging and risks”</emphasis> helps to focus on this aspect.</para>
    
    <para>For a justification of the problem analysis, and the impact on the
    requirement inception see  
    <xref linkend="h.it0ht7pktu33.1" />. </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="h.z8a4r4bndbdc.1">
    <title>System requirements</title>
    <para>With the scientific requirements in mind, the scientific
    stakeholders should define the system requirements for the hardware/software
    solution, i.e. the functional and non-functional requirements of the
    proposed system.</para>
    <para>These are the primary information about the product/solution:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      
      <listitem>
        <para>Project Scope: identifies solution system boundaries. A context diagram could be
        provided that shows a top-level view of a system and the system’s
        boundaries (section “Outline of the scope”).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The benefit of a solution: to connect the solution with scientific requirements that must be affected by the solution.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Available technologies of the context: to let non-scientific stakeholders to better understand the technological context of the scientific projects.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Provide clear statements of assumptions (section
        “Assumptions”).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Functional and non-functional requirements. It is possible to describe the solution in term of a workflow, a list of functional requirement (i.e. list the major features or user capabilities unique to the product) ( <xref linkend="h.4d2bodt7akfe.1" /> ) and provide a list of non-functional requirements (  
        <xref linkend="h.lqcugjv94utp.1" />).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify the constraints: put limitations on the ability to
        deliver a solution as envisioned restricting the solution space
        (section “Constraints”).</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <section xml:id="h.4d2bodt7akfe.1">
      <title>Use cases and system functional requirements</title>
      <para>A Use Case is a description of system behaviour in response to a
      request from one actor. We are collecting Use Cases (and related
      scenarios) starting from scientific requirements to</para>
      <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
        <listitem>
          <para>describe how an actor interacts with the system in terms of
           functions and workflows of the Physical Science
          Projects/software library/software framework;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>aim for a concise, specific and comprehensive definition of
          the requirements anticipating that trade-offs may need to be made
          if technology does not meet all requirements;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>encourage a common understanding of requirements on system
          behaviour for all the involved stakeholders;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>improve communication among WG participants, OPF members and
          Physical Science community at large;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>discover and document issues related to requirements that are
          not covered by current hardware/software solutions/current technology;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>give context to non-functional requirements.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.lqcugjv94utp.1">
      <title>System non-functional requirements</title>
      <para>This document does not list all the non-functional requirements. Between them we could remember:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">performance, availability, efficiency, reliability, scalability, security</emphasis> requirements</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>we should also take into account the <emphasis role="bold">reproducibility</emphasis> of
          the results as requirements (in particular in parallel computing
          environment);</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>think about: testable, and or (at least) traceable</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="h.okc3b56431x4.1">
    <title>In a nutshell</title>
    <para>With <emphasis role="bold">use cases/workflow/list of system requirements</emphasis>, we describe a
    possible workflow/data flow of a system and/or software library of a
    scientific project, using the template.</para>
    <para>The <emphasis role="bold">workflow</emphasis> is a view of the functional requirements of the
    system, with attached system non-functional requirements.</para>
    <para>A <emphasis role="bold">system</emphasis> could be a data analysis system or a software
    library/framework that covers some requirements.</para>
    <para>The <emphasis role="bold">proposed solution</emphasis> is a possible solution, using OPF
    hardware and software, that implement a system of a scientific project,
    or that optimize an existing solution, or that optimize the use of
    software libraries/framework used/developed by the scientific
    community</para>
    <para>The proposed solution contributes to achieve 
    the <emphasis role="bold">scientific
    requirements</emphasis> of a scientific project.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
