<!--
  Copyright (c) 2016 OpenPOWER Foundation
  
  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
  
-->

<!-- The following entity variable is used to reflect the version of the 
     template document master used for building a document.  This value
     should be set by copy of the of template used to create a new
     document and should not be changed.  Use of this value is in
     in the Abstract section in this file. --> 

<chapter version="5.0" xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
xml:id="h.d31180cwfjew.1">
  <title>Justifications</title>
  <para>In this section are provided the reasons for using the proposed
  method.</para>
  <section xml:id="h.5an7rpesemtx.1">
    <title>Requirement inception for a Physical Science project</title>
    <para>Before system requirements can be analyzed, modeled, or specified,
    they must be gathered through an elicitation process.</para>
    <para>An effective process of requirement inception (shared between all
    stakeholders) could contribute and therefore to</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>understand the workflow, starting with user
        expectations;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>help Physical Science projects maintain costs within a chosen
        envelope, helping to decide what/which ICT system to build, what the
        system must do, how it must behave (in the context of a general
        Physical Science project workflow), the properties it must exhibit,
        the qualities it must possess, and the constraints that the system
        and its development must satisfy;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>map the functionalities to the scientific requirements.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Physical Science projects are at the corner of the Physical Science
    (to open new windows in the scientific domain) and for this reason are at
    the corner of the current technology, or (more common) new technology
    should be developed to fulfill the requirements. With this in mind, a
    requirement inception process is a challenge because there are many
    different problems that the OPFPS members should manage to <emphasis role="bold">remove 
    misunderstanding between scientific and ICT stakeholders</emphasis>. Between them:</para>
    <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>The problem of scope:</emphasis></para>
    	<itemizedlist>
    	  <listitem>
    	    <para>the user (scientist/research engineer) specifies too many
    	    technical details with the risk to lose the functional aspect of
    	    their problem, and this implies a poor understanding of the
    	    functional requirements, i.e. of the workflow;</para>
    	  </listitem>
    	  <listitem>
    	    <para>and/or the boundary of the system is not well defined;</para>
    	  </listitem>
    	  <listitem>
    	    <para>to mix functional and non-functional requirements.</para>
    	  </listitem>
    	</itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>The problem of understanding:</emphasis> some of them could come from</para>
    	<itemizedlist>
    	  <listitem>
    	    <para>the users (scientist/research engineer) is not able to translate the problem domain (because the problem domain covers too many areas of knowledge) in a comprehensible way;</para>
    	  </listitem>
    	  <listitem>
    	    <para>the involved stakeholder has a full understanding of his
    	    specific problem but do not have a full understanding of the general
    	    problem domain;</para>
    	  </listitem>
    	  <listitem>
    	    <para>have trouble communicating needs to the hardware/software
    	    developers/vendors;</para>
    	  </listitem>
    	  <listitem>
    	    <para>omit information that is believed to be “obvious”;</para>
    	  </listitem>
    	  <listitem>
    	    <para>specify requirements that conflict.</para>
    	  </listitem>
    	</itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>The problem of presumption:</emphasis> Presumptions: an assumption, an idea
        that is taken to be true, and often used as the basis for other
        ideas, although it is not known for certain. In our context, this
        presumption could be made by the scientific stakeholders or by who is
        collecting requirements, usually when some aspect of the
        problem domain are not well known or understood.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis>Requirements volatility:</emphasis> the requirements change over time (see
        Section <xref linkend="h.4lpolzhmiyzr.1" /> ).</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>A Physical Science project has no similar examples that could be
    followed, due to its uniqueness. The current experiments help us in
    collecting experience, but sometimes new Physical Science projects are
    one order of magnitude bigger than current scientific projects (Big
    Science Projects).</para>
    <section xml:id="h.4lpolzhmiyzr.1">
      <title>Volatility</title>
      <para>This section is for ICT stakeholders, to understand some aspects
      of the organization of the scientific projects.</para>
      <para>About the <emphasis role="bold">volatility</emphasis>, in a Physical Science project the
      requirements could change over time for many different reasons:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the <emphasis role="bold">organizational complexity</emphasis> (and its evolution) is a
          cause of requirement volatility. Organizational goals, policies, and
          roles of intended end users all may change during the development
          of the system; to keep this problem under control it is important
          to identify the right <emphasis role="bold">stakeholders</emphasis> within the
          organization;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>the requirements are the product of the contributions of many
          individuals, and these individuals often have conflicting needs and
          goals (different scientific objects within the same project); to
          keep this under control we have proposed a template in which we try
          to extract basic information from the scientific projects (using
          some basic steps of <emphasis role="bold">problem analysis</emphasis>, see
        Section <xref linkend="h.it0ht7pktu33.1" /> );</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>increasing knowledge during the development: (i) people are
          learning/will learn new things during the development of the
          experiment, during prototyping activities or testing and
          commissioning phases, and will learn during the operations; (ii)
          one of the most important causes of requirements volatility is that
          user needs evolve over time, because the science evolves over time
          thanks to new scientific discoveries (the advance of science) that
          could change the scientific objectives and/or the workflow of the
          project itself during the development. We have foreseen an
          <emphasis role="bold">iterative process</emphasis> (see
        Section <xref linkend="h.1tyskhwshjst.2" />).</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="h.it0ht7pktu33.1">
    <title>Problem Analysis</title>
    <para>The OPFPS members should analyze the information provided by the
    scientific stakeholders to understand if this is useful to define an
    effective solution. A key element of this analysis should ensure that
    “root causes,” not just the symptoms of the problem, are identified and
    subsequently addressed by the system.</para>
    
    <para>Due to the uniqueness of the scientific projects and the complexity
    of the problem domain, the problem analysis helps to manage the problems
    of scope and understanding, because they could strongly affect the
    requirement inception. In addition, the problem analysis could avoid or
    reduce presumptions (e.g. from OPFPS members that will analyze use
    cases).</para>
    
    <para>Some aspects of the problem analysis of a scientific project that
    could be useful in the OPFPS context are:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Problem definition: ask scientific community to write a problem
        statement in an agreed format, to provide the context and to identify
        the real value of a solution;</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Try to find underlying causes of a problem to define measurable
        of a new solution. There is often a problem behind the problem or
        behind the current solution. It could be important to consists of
        finding underlying causes that may not be immediately apparent. Some
        key questions help in this process: why is it not profitable? Poor
        design? Too expensive? It is important to define which factors
        contribute to the problem and a way to measure the
        improvements.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
