<chapter version="5.0" xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title>No title</title>
  <section xml:id="h.t2f0ahjqjbf7.1">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <section xml:id="h.neyvrmz5e0u7.1">
      <title>Purpose</title>
      <para>The main purpose of this Note is to define a method and a
      template to collect Physical Science use cases from scientists and
      research engineers working on Physical Science projects in the context
      and within the scope of the OpenPOWER Foundation for Physical Science
      Workgroup.</para>
      <para>An effective method (shared between all stakeholders) could
      contribute to</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>understand the workflow, starting with user
          expectations;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>help Physical Science projects maintain costs within a chosen
          envelope;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>map the functionalities to the scientific requirements;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>remove the misunderstanding between scientific community and
          ICT stakeholders.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Section 
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.fjazhaptp3e8 describes the context
      and the main OPFPS workflow. The proposed method is a template reported
      in Section 
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.bj00l8vcud7l and justified in
      Section 
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.d31180cwfjew.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.ml4p7h2u5bgd.1">
      <title>Scope</title>
      <para>This OPFPS WG should contribute, with the foreseen deliverables
      (WP2, WP3 and WP4) (see [1]), in a more effective process of managing the
      increasing complexity of a Physical Science projects, because this could
      help to take the ICT system under control or to find new solutions that
      are at the corner of the ICT industry.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.zhspm95fi9e9.1">
      <title>Stakeholders identification</title>
      <para>This section describes the intended audience of this Note and of
      the OPFPS WG.</para>
      <para>Stakeholders are individuals, groups, organizations who are
      actively involved in the scientific project, are affected by its
      outcome or are able to influence its outcome. All stakeholders could be
      OPFPS members. The stakeholders are:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Physical Science community: stakeholders that should provide
          requirements:</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Scientists</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Research engineers</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>ICT community: stakeholders that could provide a
          solution</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>WG participants: members of both community that should provide
          support in collecting, analyzing and categorizing
          requirements.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.64nbpuogu2cr.1">
      <title>Acronyms</title>
      <para>OPF = OpenPOWER Foundation</para>
      <para>OPFPS = OpenPOWER Foundation for Physical Science</para>
      <para>WG = Workgroup</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.k597y24tvijd.1">
      <title>Definitions</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Problem analysis: Problem analysis involves identifying the
          overriding problem and establishing the causes and effects related to
          that problem.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Scientific objectives: The scientific objectives are the goals
          of a scientific project. The scientific requirements are needed to
          reach the scientific objectives.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Scientific requirements A) are high-level statements that
          are needed to reach the scientific objectives/goals of the scientific
          project (and of the scientific organisation that manage the project).
          They describe the results that the project will achieve, and the
          metrics which will be used to measure its success. Scientific
          requirements must be achieved to provide value for the scientific
          project.  B) A requirement of a physical science experiment
          described in terms of the parameters to perform science (e.g. minimum
          sensitivity of a telescope, minimum angular resolution). </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Example: we need to observe N celestial objects in T
          time.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Example: we need to repoint the telescope in 30 seconds.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>System requirements: requirements of the HW/SW solution, i.e.
          the functional and non-functional requirements of the proposed
          system. Functional requirements define a function or a behaviour
          of a system (a list of the major features or user capabilities unique
          to the product). Non-functional requirements impose qualities
          and constraints on the design or implementation (such as performance,
          security, or reliability).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>System: the solution that should be proposed/developed.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.9w8eqfcov7xi.1">
      <title>Reference</title>
      <para>[1] OPFPS charter</para>
      <para>[2] SEI, “A Framework for Software Product Line Practice, Version
      5.0”, 2012,
      http://www.sei.cmu.edu/productlines/frame_report/req_eng.htm</para>
      <para>[3] Alistair Cockburn, “Writing Effective Use Cases”, Addison
      Wesley, 2000</para>
      <para>[4] M. Christel, K. Chang, “Issues in Requirements Elicitation”,
      CMU/SEI-92-TR-012, 1992</para>
      <para>[5] Macaulay, Linda, Fowler, Chris, Kirby, Mark, and Hutt, Andrew.
      USTM: A New Approach to Requirements Specification. Interacting with
      Computers 2(1):92-118, April 1990.</para>
      <para>[6] Robin F. Goldsmith, JD, “Conventional Requirements Model Flaw
      Misses REAL Business Requirements”, 2007, available at 
      <link xl:href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.gopromanagement.com&amp;sa=D&amp;ust=1493996251691000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFeYz4qDqEpGVfWdbi5gyI1Xp3X-A">

        <citetitle>
        https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.gopromanagement.com&amp;sa=D&amp;ust=1493996251691000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFeYz4qDqEpGVfWdbi5gyI1Xp3X-A</citetitle>
      </link> </para>
      <para>[7] Robin F. Goldsmith, JD, “BAs Will Falter Until They Learn to
      Discover REAL, Business Requirements”, IEEE 17th Requirements Engineering
      Conference (RE’09), 2009</para>
      <para>[8] Dean Leffingwell, Don Widrig, “Managing Software Requirements:
      A Use Case Approach”, 2nd Edition, 2003</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="h.fjazhaptp3e8.1">
    <title>The context</title>
    <section xml:id="h.x8ybuq41czt2.1">
      <title>Physical Science</title>
      <para>Physical Science is any science concerned with nonliving matter,
      energy, and the physical properties of the Universe, such as physics,
      chemistry, astronomy, and geology.</para>
      <para>In this context, the OPFPS WG cover the following aspects:
      <superscript>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt1</superscript>
      <superscript>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt2</superscript></para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Needs of Big Science Projects</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Needs of experiments at laboratory level</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Software frameworks</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Software libraries</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.1tyskhwshjst.1">
      <title>OPFPS workflow</title>
      <para>A basic OPFPS workflow could be summarized as the following:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>requirement inception (eliciting requirements), to collect
          functional requirements (e.g. as use cases) and related
          non-functional requirements from scientific community (from
          scientific stakeholders);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>requirement analysis, determining and refining the system
          requirements, to provide a coherent view of the use cases, and to
          resolve misunderstanding (from OPFPS members);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>system modelling: deriving a logical workflow/dataflow model of
          the system, to derive commonalities between different use cases (from
          OPFPS members);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>provide a solution (from ICT stakeholders)
          <superscript>
          <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt3</superscript>
          <superscript>
          <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt4</superscript>.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The proposed process is iterative, so that reference solutions can
      be reworked in the light of increased knowledge. Iteration means that the
      scientific stakeholders should provide use cases and non-functional
      requirements and refine them based on feedbacks received by other
      stakeholders or by the OPFPS members.</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The OPFPS members are available to update the common workflow
          for each new use case that is added or updated.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="h.bj00l8vcud7l.1">
    <title>Requirement inception method</title>
    <section xml:id="h.uc5h5eptiqau.1">
      <title>Method</title>
      <para>Two main steps are foreseen:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Description of the scientific problem and related scientific
          requirements: In this context, the WG asks scientific stakeholders to
          provide an overview/summary of their problem (with a short
          description of the scientific objectives), and to provide scientific
          requirements that could be measurable; this helps to identify the
          scientific requirements for which a possible HW/SW solution has the
          greatest impact. The main purpose is to provide a real value of the
          proposed solution to the users;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Definition of use cases and identification of system
          requirements (functional and non-functional) that are used as input
          to define a solution.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>The main purpose is to identify system functional and system
      non-functional requirements that provide real value for the
      scientific project, i.e. to help to fulfill scientific
      requirements. System functional requirements define a function
      or a behaviour of a system. System non-functional
      requirements impose qualities and constraints on the design or
      implementation of the system (such as performance, security, or
      reliability).</para>
      <para>In Section 
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.hifw4g34594y we report the
      template, that reflects the two steps depicted above. Sections 
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.ivq40yd8cvjz, 
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.z8a4r4bndbdc and 
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.k1sz7cwj362y report a
      justification of the template. Section 
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.okc3b56431x4 is a summary.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.hifw4g34594y.1">
      <title>The template</title>
      <para>Scientists, research engineers, hardware and software developers
      and vendors do not have a common language and terms; all WG participants
      need details and guidance that organise the information in a uniform way.
      For the purpose of this work the use cases must be readable by all
      involved stakeholders.</para>
      <para>In this section we propose a template to collect Physical
      Science use cases from scientific stakeholders. This template could
      help to collect problem statements and solution requirements. With
      this template we will help stakeholders to extract useful information
      from their “problem” to better understand:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>which scientific requirement the proposed solution should
          fulfill and</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>to better identify use cases/workflows/functional requirements
          and the context;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>to reduce problem of scope, understanding and presumptions
          (check Section 
          <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.5an7rpesemtx);</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>to avoid to omit information that is mandatory to extract a
          workflows
          <superscript>
          <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt5</superscript>
          <superscript>
          <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt6</superscript>;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>to enable solutions with a real benefit for
          scientists.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>The template is organized in sections and where some key questions
      or suggestions are presents.</para>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="error_section" />
      </para>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="error_section" />
      </para>
      <para>The following sections report a justification of the
      template.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.ivq40yd8cvjz.1">
      <title>Problem analysis and scientific requirements</title>
      <para>It is important to have a summary of the problem that the
      scientific project covers/wants to resolve. The scientific stakeholders
      should extract some basic information from their problem domain.</para>
      <para>The section “Scientific problem analysis” helps OPFPS members and
      ICT stakeholders to focus on useful information from the problem domain
      of the scientific project. In fact, this is a basic problem
      analysis procedure that help OPF members and ICT stakeholders to
      identify the real value for scientists in the resolution of their
      problems.</para>
      <para>The first step is the identification of scientific objectives,
      i.e. the goals of the scientific project (section “Scientific
      objectives”).</para>
      <para>The scientific requirements are needed to reach the scientific
      objectives. The scientific stakeholders should identify the scientific
      requirements of the project (in analogy with the “business
      requirements” for an enterprise) for which the proposed solution has the
      maximum impact, and to provide a metric that will be used to measure
      the effectiveness of the proposed solution (section “Scientific
      requirements and problem definition”).</para>
      <para>The primary reason products/systems don’t help to improve/satisfy
      the right scientific requirements is because the scientific requirements
      have not been identified adequately or they have not been properly
      understood by the ICT stakeholders (section “Underlying causes of a
      problem”).</para>
      <para>This step will help to define a reference solution for a
      workflow/system that will provide a real value for the scientific project
      (section “Benefits of a solution”).</para>
      <para>For a justification of the problem analysis, and the impact on the
      requirement inception see Section 
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.it0ht7pktu33 </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.z8a4r4bndbdc.1">
      <title>System requirements</title>
      <para>With the scientific requirements in mind the scientific
      stakeholders should define the system requirements of the HW/SW
      solution, i.e. the functional and non-functional requirements of the
      proposed system.</para>
      <para>These are the main information about the product/solution:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Product Vision: describes what the product is (section “Vision
          of the solution”).
          <superscript>
          <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt9</superscript>
          <superscript>
          <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt10</superscript></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Project Scope: identifies what portion of the ultimate
          scientific project the current product/system will address,
          definition of solution system boundaries. A context diagram could be
          provided that shows a top-level view of a system and the system’s
          boundaries (section “Scope”).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Provide clear statements of assumptions (section
          “Assumptions”).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Functional requirements: It is possible to describe the
          solution in term of a workflow, a list of functional requirement or a
          use case (sections 
          <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.4d2bodt7akfe). List the major
          features or user capabilities unique to the new product. For
          non-functional requirements check section 
          <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.lqcugjv94utp for more details.
          See section “Description of the workflow/main functional and
          non-functional requirements”.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Identify the constraints: put limitations on the ability to
          deliver a solution as envisioned restricting the solution space
          (section “Constraints”).</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <section xml:id="h.4d2bodt7akfe.1">
        <title>Use cases and system functional requirements</title>
        <para>A Use Case is a description of system behaviour in response to a
        request from one actor. We are collecting Use Cases (and related
        scenarios) starting from scientific requirements to</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>describe how an actor interacts with the system in terms of
             functions and workflows of the Physical Science
            Projects/software library/software framework;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Aim for a concise, specific and comprehensive definition of
            the requirements anticipating that trade-offs may need to be made
            if technology does not meet all requirements;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>encourage a common understanding of requirements on system
            behaviour for all the involved stakeholders;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>improve communication among WG participants, OPF members and
            Physical Science community at large;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>discover and document issues related to requirements that are
            not covered by current hw/sw solutions/current technology;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>give context to non-functional requirements.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="h.lqcugjv94utp.1">
        <title>System non-functional requirements</title>
        <para>Not-exhaustive list of non-functional requirements (TBC):</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Quality requirements</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Constraints </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>We should take also into account the reproducibility of
            the results as a requirements (in particular in parallel computing
            environment);</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Think about: testable, and or (at least) traceable? Why
            traceability?</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.k1sz7cwj362y.1">
      <title>The system (the solution)</title>
      <para>The system, for which we collect system requirements could be a
      workflow or a dataflow (or part of a workflow) of a solution for a
      scientific project, a software library of a software framework that could
      be used as part of a workflow or a dataflow.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.okc3b56431x4.1">
      <title>In a nutshell</title>
      <para>With use cases/workflow/list of system requirements we describe a
      possible workflow/dataflow of a system and/or software library of a
      scientific project, using the template.</para>
      <para>The workflow is a view of the functional requirements of the
      system, with attached system non-functional requirements.</para>
      <para>A system could be a data analysis system or a software
      library/framework that covers some system requirements.</para>
      <para>The proposed solution is a possibile solution, using OPF
      hardware and software, that implement a system of a scientific project,
      or that optimize an existing solution, or that optimize the use of
      software libraries/framework used/developed by the scientific
      community</para>
      <para>The proposed solution contributes to achieving the scientific
      requirements of a scientific project.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="h.d31180cwfjew.1">
    <title>Justifications</title>
    <para>In this section are provided the reasons for using the proposed
    method.</para>
    <section xml:id="h.5an7rpesemtx.1">
      <title>Requirement inception for a Physical Science project</title>
      <para>Before system requirements can be analyzed, modeled, or specified
      they must be gathered through an elicitation process.</para>
      <para>An effective process of requirement inception (shared between all
      stakeholders) could contribute and therefore to</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>understand the workflow, starting with user
          expectations;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>help Physical Science projects maintain costs within a chosen
          envelope, helping to decide what/which ICT system to build, what the
          system must do, how it must behave (in the context of the general
          Physical Science project workflow), the properties it must exhibit,
          the qualities it must possess, and the constraints that the system
          and its development must satisfy;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>map the functionalities to the scientific requirements.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Physical Science projects are at the corner of the Physical Science
      (to open new windows in the scientific domain) and for this reason are at
      the corner of the current technology, or (more common) new technology
      should be developed to fulfill the requirements. With this in mind, a
      requirement inception process is a challenge because there are many
      different problems that the OPFPS members should manage to remove the
      misunderstanding between scientific and ICT stakeholders:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Problem of scope:</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the user (scientist/research engineer) specifies too many
          technical details with the risk to loose the functional aspect of
          their problem, and this implies a poor understanding of the
          functional requirements, i.e. of the workflow;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>and/or the boundary of the system is not well defined;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>to mix functional and non-functional requirements.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Problem of understanding: some of them could came from</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>the users (scientist/research engineer) is not able to
          translate his problem domain (because the problem domain is very
          extended) in a comprehensible way;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>the involved stakeholder has a full understanding of his
          specific problem but do not have a full understanding of the general
          problem domain;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>have trouble communicating needs to the hw/sw
          developers/vendors,</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>omit information that is believed to be “obvious”,</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>specify requirements that conflicts.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Problem of presumption: Presumptions: an assumption, an an idea
          that is taken to be true, and often used as the basis for other
          ideas, although it is not known for certain. In our context this
          presumption could be made by the scientific stakeholders or by who is
          collection requirements (WG members), usually when some aspect of the
          problem domain are not well known or understood.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Requirements volatility: the requirements change over time (see
          Section 
          <xref linkend="error_section" /> h.4lpolzhmiyzr).</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>A Physical Science project has no similar examples that could be
      followed, due to its uniqueness. The current experiments help us in
      collecting experience, but sometimes new Physical Science projects are
      one order of magnitude bigger than current scientific projects (e.g. Big
      Science Projects).</para>
      <section xml:id="h.4lpolzhmiyzr.1">
        <title>Volatility</title>
        <para>This section is for ICT stakeholders, to understand some aspects
        of the organisation of the scientific projects.</para>
        <para>About the volatility, in a Physical Science project the
        requirements could change over time for many different reasons:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>the organizational complexity (and its evolution) is a
            cause of requirement volatility. Organizational goals, policies and
            roles of intended end users all may change during the development
            of the system; to keep this problem under control it is important
            to identify the right stakeholders within the
            organisation;</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>the requirements are the product of the contributions of many
            individuals, and these individuals often have conflicting needs and
            goals (different scientific objects within the same project); to
            keep this under control we have proposed a template in which we try
            to extract basic information from the scientific projects (using
            some basic steps of problem analysis);</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>increasing knowledge during the development: (i) people are
            learning/will learn new things during the development of the
            experiment, during prototyping activities or during testing and
            commissioning phases, and will learn during the operations; (ii)
            one of the most important cause of requirements volatility is that
            user needs evolve over time, because the science evolves over time
            thanks to new scientific discoveries (the advance of science) that
            could change the scientific objectives (and/or) the workflow of the
            project itself during the development. We have foreseen an
            iterative process.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.it0ht7pktu33.1">
      <title>Problem Analysis</title>
      <para>The problem analysis is for OPFPS members and ICT stakeholders, to
      better understand the scientific project.</para>
      <para>Due to the uniqueness of the scientific projects and the complexity
      of the problem domain, the problem analysis helps to manage the problems
      of scope and understanding, because they could strongly affect the
      requirement inception. In addition, the problem analysis could avoid or
      reduce presumptions (e.g. from OPFPS members that will analyze use
      cases).</para>
      <para>The OPFPS members should analyse the information provided by the
      scientific stakeholders to understand if this is useful to define an
      effective solution. A key element of this analysis should ensure that
      “root causes,” not just the symptoms of the problem, are identified and
      subsequently addressed by the system.</para>
      <para>Some aspects of the problem analysis of scientific project that
      could be useful in the OPFPS context are:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Problem definition: ask scientific community to write a problem
          statement in an agreed format, to provide the context and to identify
          the real value of a solution;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Try to find underlying causes of a problem to define measurable
          of a new solution. There is often a problem behind the problem or
          behind the current solution. It could be important to consists of
          finding underlying causes that may not be immediately apparent. Some
          key questions help in this process: why is it not profitable? Poor
          design? Too expensive? It is important to define which factors
          contribute to the problem and a way to measure the
          improvements.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="h.i7w45c2bgap.1">
      <title />
      <para>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> ftnt_ref1 
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> mailto:andrea.bulgarelli@inaf.it </para>
      <para>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt_ref1I suggest to also highlight the
      aspect of challenging hardware requirements</para>
      <para>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt_ref2Ok</para>
      <para>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt_ref3Within OPF a number of people
      make a strong case about the Foundation not being about solutions and
      thus being neutral wrt to solutions. This was also an issue raised in the
      context of a draft version of the WG's charter. I would formulate: Enable
      ICT stakeholders to provide suitable solutions.</para>
      <para>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt_ref4ok</para>
      <para>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt_ref5I am not sure that I understand
      this statement. Is the following paraphrase correct? "to avoid missing
      any information describing relevant aspects of a workflow."</para>
      <para>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt_ref6I agree, thanks</para>
      <para>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt_ref7There may be no "current
      solution" as it is about a future experiment. In general, I would suggest
      not to use the term "solution" in this context. See next comment.</para>
      <para>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt_ref8I fully agree, Thanks to help to
      clarify these concepts.</para>
      <para>I have removed any reference to the term "solution"</para>
      <para>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt_ref9I have often seen it becoming a
      mistake that requirements were communicated in terms of anticipated
      solutions. This limits the design space as the problem specifier tend to
      have a less good overview on possible solutions.</para>
      <para>
      <xref linkend="error_section" /> cmnt_ref10I agree. I have removed this
      section from the template. Let's scientists specify only
      requirements</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="error_section">
    <title>Conversion Errors</title>
    <para>This section contains errors that could not be resolved by the
    mkbook.py program.</para>
    <para>ftnt1</para>
    <para></para>
    <para></para>
    <para>mailto:opfps@openpowerfoundation.org</para>
    <para>h.t2f0ahjqjbf7</para>
    <para>h.t2f0ahjqjbf7</para>
    <para>h.neyvrmz5e0u7</para>
    <para>h.neyvrmz5e0u7</para>
    <para>h.ml4p7h2u5bgd</para>
    <para>h.ml4p7h2u5bgd</para>
    <para>h.zhspm95fi9e9</para>
    <para>h.zhspm95fi9e9</para>
    <para>h.64nbpuogu2cr</para>
    <para>h.64nbpuogu2cr</para>
    <para>h.k597y24tvijd</para>
    <para>h.k597y24tvijd</para>
    <para>h.9w8eqfcov7xi</para>
    <para>h.9w8eqfcov7xi</para>
    <para>h.fjazhaptp3e8</para>
    <para>h.fjazhaptp3e8</para>
    <para>h.x8ybuq41czt2</para>
    <para>h.x8ybuq41czt2</para>
    <para>h.1tyskhwshjst</para>
    <para>h.1tyskhwshjst</para>
    <para>h.rsgn70bn02ih</para>
    <para>h.rsgn70bn02ih</para>
    <para>h.bj00l8vcud7l</para>
    <para>h.bj00l8vcud7l</para>
    <para>h.uc5h5eptiqau</para>
    <para>h.uc5h5eptiqau</para>
    <para>h.hifw4g34594y</para>
    <para>h.hifw4g34594y</para>
    <para>h.ivq40yd8cvjz</para>
    <para>h.ivq40yd8cvjz</para>
    <para>h.z8a4r4bndbdc</para>
    <para>h.z8a4r4bndbdc</para>
    <para>h.4d2bodt7akfe</para>
    <para>h.4d2bodt7akfe</para>
    <para>h.lqcugjv94utp</para>
    <para>h.lqcugjv94utp</para>
    <para>h.k1sz7cwj362y</para>
    <para>h.k1sz7cwj362y</para>
    <para>h.okc3b56431x4</para>
    <para>h.okc3b56431x4</para>
    <para>h.d31180cwfjew</para>
    <para>h.d31180cwfjew</para>
    <para>h.5an7rpesemtx</para>
    <para>h.5an7rpesemtx</para>
    <para>h.4lpolzhmiyzr</para>
    <para>h.4lpolzhmiyzr</para>
    <para>h.it0ht7pktu33</para>
    <para>h.it0ht7pktu33</para>
    <para>h.fjazhaptp3e8</para>
    <para>h.bj00l8vcud7l</para>
    <para>h.d31180cwfjew</para>
    <para>cmnt1</para>
    <para>cmnt2</para>
    <para>cmnt3</para>
    <para>cmnt4</para>
    <para>h.hifw4g34594y</para>
    <para>h.ivq40yd8cvjz</para>
    <para>h.z8a4r4bndbdc</para>
    <para>h.k1sz7cwj362y</para>
    <para>h.okc3b56431x4</para>
    <para>h.5an7rpesemtx</para>
    <para>cmnt5</para>
    <para>cmnt6</para>
    <para></para>
    <para></para>
    <para>cmnt7</para>
    <para>cmnt8</para>
    <para>h.it0ht7pktu33</para>
    <para>cmnt9</para>
    <para>cmnt10</para>
    <para>h.4d2bodt7akfe</para>
    <para>h.lqcugjv94utp</para>
    <para>h.4lpolzhmiyzr</para>
    <para>ftnt_ref1</para>
    <para>mailto:andrea.bulgarelli@inaf.it</para>
    <para>cmnt_ref1</para>
    <para>cmnt_ref2</para>
    <para>cmnt_ref3</para>
    <para>cmnt_ref4</para>
    <para>cmnt_ref5</para>
    <para>cmnt_ref6</para>
    <para>cmnt_ref7</para>
    <para>cmnt_ref8</para>
    <para>cmnt_ref9</para>
    <para>cmnt_ref10</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
